We're now going to talk a little bit about an issue that's of interest according to
下面我们来浅谈一些科学家感兴趣而
scientists, but may not be of much interest to engineers.
工程师并不太感兴趣的问题
So if you're an engineer you can just ignore this video.
所以 诸位工程师可以忽视这集视频
In computer science, there's been a debate going on for maybe a 100 years about the
在计算机科学领域 有一场持续百年的争论
relationship between feature vector representations of concepts and
关于特征向量的概念表示和
representations of concepts by their relations to other concepts.
概念间相互联系表示的关系
And the learning algorithm we've just seen for family trees has a lot to say about
我们刚看到的系谱图学习算法跟这个争论有很大关系
that debate. We're now going to make a brief diversion
我们现在对认知科学做一个简要的介绍
into cognitive science. There's been a long debate between two
长期以来有一个争论
rival theories of what it means to have a concept.
对于什么是概念 有两种不同的理论
The feature says a concept is a big set of semantic features.
特征理论认为一个概念是一个很大的语义特征集合
This is good for explaining similarities between concepts.
这对于解释概念之间的相似性很好
And it's convenient for things like machine learning.
而且对机器学习这类领域很便利
Because we like to deal with vectors of activities.
因为我们喜欢处理向量
The structuralist theory says that the meaning of a concept lies in its
结构理论认为概念的含义在于
relationships to other concepts. So conceptual knowledge is best expressed
它和其他概念之间的关系 因此概念上的知识最好
not as a big vector, but as a relational graph.
不用向量来表征 而是用关系图
In the early 1970s, Marvin Minsky use the limitations of perceptrons as evidence
在1970年代初 Marvin Minsky使用感知机的限制作为证据
against featured actors in favor of relational graph representations.
反对特征向量 偏向于关系图表示法
My belief is that both sides in this debate are wrong because both sides
我认为这两方都不对 因为它们都
believe that the two theories are rivals and they're not rivals at all.
相信这两种理论是敌对的 但其实不是这样的
A neural net can use vectors of semantic features to implement a relational graph.
一个神经网络可以使用语义特征向量来实现一个关系图
In the neural network that learns family trees, we can think of explicit inference
在学习系谱图的神经网络中 我们可以考虑显式推导
as I give you person one and I give you a relationship then you tell me person two.
当我给你第一个人和他的关系 你就能说出第二个人
And to arrive at that conclusion, the neural net doesn't follow a whole bunch of
为了推出这个结论 神经网络不用按照一系列
rules of inference. It just passes information forward through
推导规则 它通过网络将信息向前传递
the net. As far as the neural net is concerned, the
在神经网络的角度
answer is intuitively obvious. Now if you look at the details of what's
在直觉上答案是明显的 如果你对细节保持观察
happening, there's lots of probabilistic features that are influencing each other.
就会发现有很多概率特征在互相影响着
We call these microfeatures to sort of emphasize they're not like explicit
我们之所以叫它们微特征 是为了强调它们不像
conscious features. In a real brain, there might be millions
显式的意识特征 在真实的大脑中 可能有
of them and millions of interactions, and as a result of all these interactions, we
上百万这种微特征和相互联系 因为这种相互联系
can make one step of explicit inference. And that's what we believe is involved in
我们可以在显式推理上更进一步 即 我们所相信的是
just seeing the answer to something. There are no intervening conscious steps,
我们所看到的一些问题的答案 这里没有介于中间的意识的阶段
but nevertheless there's a lot of computation going on in the interactions
但是有很多在神经元之间相互作用的计算
of neurons. So we may use explicit rules for conscious
我们可以使用显式的规则来进行有意识的精密推理
deliberate reasoning, but a lot of our common sense reasoning, particularly
但是很多我们认为是常识的推理
analogical reasoning, works by just seeing the answer, with no conscious intervening
尤其是反逻辑的推理 只在看到答案时有效 没有介于之间的意识过程
steps. And even when we do conscious reasoning,
即使当我们做一些意识推理
we have to have some way of just seeing which rules apply, in order to avoid an
我们不得不考虑一些方法来观察什么规则适用 为了避免
infinite regress. So, many people, when they think about
无限的回归 因此 当很多人考虑
implementing a relational graph in a neural net, just assume that you should
在神经网络中实现一个关系图 只用假设你应该
make a neuron correspond to a node in the relational graph and a connection between,
使一个神经元与关系图中的一个节点连接
two neurons correspond to a binary relationship.
和两个神经元与一个二进制关系图的连接
But this method doesn't work. For a start, the relationships come in
但是这个方法是无效的 首先 关系
different flavors. They're are different kinds of
有不同的偏好 它们是不同种类的
relationship. Like mother of, or aunt of and, a
关系 比如母亲的关系 姑姑的关系 和
connection in a neural net only has a strength.
神经网络中的一个连接仅仅有一个好处
It doesn't come in different types. Also we need to do we turn around your
它不是不同类型的连接 我们也需要转变关系
relationships like'a' is between'b' and'c'.
比如A在B和C之间
We still don't know for sure the right way to implement relational knowledge in a
我们仍然不知道在神经网络中实现知识关系正确的方式
neural net. But it seems very probable that many
但是很可能
neurons are used for representing each of the concepts we know, and each of those
很多神经元被用作我们所知道的概念 每一个
neurons is probably involved in dealing with many different concepts.
神经元很可能负责处理很多不同的概念
This is called a distributed representation.
这被称作分布式表征
It's a many to many mapping between concepts and neurons.
这是一个多对多的在概念和神经元之间的映射 翻译 Naiding Zhou